Guide to the University Finance Reference Collection, 1948-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
University Finance Reference collection 1948-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
1.6 Linear Feet approx. 700 Items
The University Finances Reference Collection contains files of publications, reports, news clippings, and memoranda related to the University's investments, fundraising, budgeting and similar financial matters. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The University Finances Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Collection Overview
The University Finances Reference Collection contains files of publications, reports, news clippings, and memoranda related to the University's investments, fundraising, budgeting and other financial matters. Major subjects include fundraising campaigns, and endowment management. The collection includes several publications produced to explain the University's finances to students.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century
Duke University -- Finance
Related Material
Duke University. Annual Report/Financial Report, 1947/48-
Duke University Archives
Year in Review, 2001/2002-2006/2007
http://www.yearinreview.duke.edu/
Financial Reports
http://www.finsvc.duke.edu/resources/docs/financial_reports.pdf
Annual report of Duke University
http://dukespace.lib.duke.edu/dspace/handle/10161/31/browse-title
Fifth Decade Program Records, 1964-1973
Duke University Archives
Office of the President Records
Duke University Archives
Office of University Development Records
Duke University Archives
Office of Institutional Advancement Records
Duke University Archives
Founders' Society Reference Collection, 1980-1997
Duke University Archives
James B. Duke Society Reference Collection, 1997-ongoing
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Annual fund, 1981-2001 (Box 1)
  - Annual fund, Davison Club, 1980
  - Annual fund, Dean's Club, 1986-1988
  - Annual fund, Washington Duke Club, [1999]
  - Annual fund, William Preston Few Association, 1989-1992
  - The Bean Counter's Guide [1997, a guide to Duke's finances]
  - The Campaign for Duke, 1998-2003. Brochures
  - The Campaign for Duke, 1998-2003. News Releases and Clippings
  - The Campaign for Duke, 1998-2003. Benchmark [newsletter], incomplete, 1998-2003
  - Clippings, to 1969
  - Clippings, 1970-1979
  - Clippings, 1980-1989
  - Clippings, 1990-1999
  - Committee on Bequests, 1963-1966
  - To Cross a Threshhold, publication, 1984
  - Duke Dimensions: a Magazine for Undergraduates, 1981 [guide to Duke's finances]
  - The Duke Endowment
  - Duke Management Company, News Releases and Clippings, 1990-
  - Duke Management Company, Building Duke University's Endowment, 1995
  - Duke Management Company, Newsletters, 1992-2000
  - Duke University Development Campaign, 1950-1952. Campaigner's Kit
  - Duke University Development Campaign, 1950-1952. Handbooks
  - Duke University Development Campaign, 1950-1952. Mailings to Faculty/Staff/Students
  - Duke University Development Campaign, 1950-1952. Promotional
  - Duke University Development Campaign, 1950-1952. Reports
  - Endowments, performing and dramatic arts
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. A Time for Greatness at Duke
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Brochures (Box 2)
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Clippings
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Mailings
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Newsletters
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Planning memos
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Reporting Progress
  - The Epoch Campaign, 1973-1977. Where do you think you're going, America? [New York Times advertising supplement, October 7, 1973]
  - The Fifth Decade Campaign, 1964-1973
  - Grants to Trinity & Duke
  - Grants: clippings
  - Grants: Ford Foundation, 1960
  - Grants: Supplementary proposal. University Science Development Program, 1972
  - Loyalty Fund, 1953/54, 1977/78
  - Memoranda
  - Office of Planned Giving: For the future of Duke, 1978/79
  - Office of Planned Giving: Planned philanthropy for the future of Duke, 1980-1985
  - Office of University Development: Annual Report, 2006/07
  - Planned Giving, 1971-1981
  - A Report on the financial needs and resources of Duke University / Keating, Brown & Co., 1948
  - To Endow, To Enrich, Annual Report, 1978-1979
  - A Capital Idea, Annual Report, 1979-1980